<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sessions on AMS 343: History of Text Messaging</title>
    <link>https://gwijthoff.github.io/texting/sessions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sessions on AMS 343: History of Text Messaging</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><atom:link href="https://gwijthoff.github.io/texting/sessions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Week 1</title>
      <link>https://gwijthoff.github.io/texting/sessions/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gwijthoff.github.io/texting/sessions/1/</guid>
      <description>session notes
Introducing ourselves; deciding on course logistics; outlining units, sessions, and themes for the semester.
📚 Read:  Nothing  📺 Watch:  Nothing  🎧 Listen:  Nothing  ✏️ Write:  Still Nothing  ❀
Related Links on community technology Philly Community Wireless Project
Community Tech NY</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 10</title>
      <link>https://gwijthoff.github.io/texting/sessions/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gwijthoff.github.io/texting/sessions/10/</guid>
      <description>Before Class 📚 Read:  Amaranth Borsuk, The Book, Chapter 1: The Book as Object, pp. 1-60 [only if you have time] Treharne and Willan, Text Technologies, &amp;ldquo;Writing on Cellulose&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Writing on Animal Skin,&amp;rdquo; pp. 60–77  📺 Watch:  telegraph operator racing a T9 texting champion interview with Verena Lepper on her digital Egyptology research of Elephantine Island, reconstructing papyrus rolls  to be launched 2021, but early version of site here    ✏️ Write:  an answer to this #response-question:  Borsuk defines the book as &amp;ldquo;a portable data storage and distribution method&amp;rdquo; whose &amp;ldquo;changing form is bound up with that of its changing content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 11</title>
      <link>https://gwijthoff.github.io/texting/sessions/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gwijthoff.github.io/texting/sessions/11/</guid>
      <description>🚧
Visitor: Stephanie Luescher, project manager of Princeton Geniza Project
Before Class 📚 Read:  Borsuk, The Book, Chapter 2: the Book as Content Greetham, David. “A History of Textual Scholarship.” In The Cambridge Companion to Textual Scholarship, edited by Julia Flanders and Neil Fraistat, 16–41. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 2013. Cohen, Matt. “Time and the Bibliographer: A Meditation on the Spirit of Book Studies.” Textual Cultures 13, no. 1 (April 15, 2020): 179–206.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 12</title>
      <link>https://gwijthoff.github.io/texting/sessions/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gwijthoff.github.io/texting/sessions/12/</guid>
      <description>🚧
Before Class 📚 Read:  TK  ❀
Practicum None.
❀
Related Links </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2</title>
      <link>https://gwijthoff.github.io/texting/sessions/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gwijthoff.github.io/texting/sessions/2/</guid>
      <description>session notes • slides
Overview of the roots of SMS as a technical standard, its current state, and its proposed replacement: the Rich Communication Standard (RCS).
Make sure everyone is set up with course platforms, and pair up for the semester&amp;rsquo;s letter writing.
Before Class 📚 Read:  Scott B. Weingart, &amp;ldquo;The Route of a Text Message, a Love Story&amp;rdquo;  🎧 Listen:  &amp;ldquo;Thank You, Text.&amp;rdquo; Reset podcast episode (26min)  📺 Watch:  A Brief Look at Texting and the Internet in Film (2014, 5min)  ✏️ Write:  answers to these #response-questions:  A single text message has to pass through many &amp;ldquo;layers&amp;rdquo; of translation and transmission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3</title>
      <link>https://gwijthoff.github.io/texting/sessions/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gwijthoff.github.io/texting/sessions/3/</guid>
      <description>session notes • slides
Visitor: Houman Saberi, Community Tech NY
A brief introduction to a number of grassroots, activist organizations working toward digital equity in the U.S. who define themselves as &amp;ldquo;community technologists.&amp;rdquo;
The key differences between one-to-one messaging, one-to-few group chats, and one-to-many broadcasting. The divide between local ties and global connection.
Before Class 📚 Read:  Greta Byrum, “Building the People’s Internet.” Urban Omnibus Familiarize yourselves with:  Community Technology Collective Teaching Community Technology Handbook, ed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 4</title>
      <link>https://gwijthoff.github.io/texting/sessions/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gwijthoff.github.io/texting/sessions/4/</guid>
      <description>session notes Before Class 📚 Read:  Ahmed, Syed Ishtiaque, Nusrat Jahan Mim, and Steven J. Jackson, “Residual Mobilities: Infrastructural Displacement and Post-Colonial Computing in Bangladesh” two excerpts from André Brock, Distributed Blackness: African American Cybercultures (2020)  &amp;ldquo;The Soft Bigotry of Low Information Expectations&amp;rdquo; pp. 40-41 &amp;ldquo;…and Mobile Digital Practice&amp;rdquo; pp. 136-38    📺 Watch:  Meet the People Building Their Own Internet in Detroit, Vice (12:12)  🎧 Listen:  Interview with Nicol Turner Lee, director of the Center for Technology Innovation at the Brookings Institution, on the FCC&amp;rsquo;s Broadband podcast (29:22)  ✏️ Write:  answers to these #response-questions:  How do Ahmed et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 5</title>
      <link>https://gwijthoff.github.io/texting/sessions/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gwijthoff.github.io/texting/sessions/5/</guid>
      <description>session notes
Visitor: Devren Washington, Movement Alliance Project
This class session will be a collaboration with the Philly Community Wireless Project.
Before Class 📚 Read:  Breitbart, Joshua, Naveen Lakshmipathy, and Sascha D. Meinrath. “The Philadelphia Story: Learning from a Municipal Wireless Pioneer.” New America Foundation (2007) Introduction, Christina Dunbar-Hester, Low Power to the People: Pirates, Protest, and Politics in FM Radio Activism (MIT Press, 2014) Devren Washington, &amp;ldquo;Philly School District shouldn’t have to pay Comcast a dime to get kids online,&amp;rdquo; The Philadelphia Inquirer (Aug 26, 2020)  ✏️ Write:  a letter to your classmate answers to these #response-questions:  What happened to municipal wireless in the 2000s in Philadelphia, and what is the status of municipal wireless elsewhere today?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 6</title>
      <link>https://gwijthoff.github.io/texting/sessions/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gwijthoff.github.io/texting/sessions/6/</guid>
      <description>session notes
Visitor: Jérémie Lumbroso, Princeton Computer Science (1:30–2:30)
Note: Election Day is a month away. Are you all set up to vote? Please see Princeton&amp;rsquo;s Vote100 Project.
Note: this is the University&amp;rsquo;s midterm examination week.
Before Class 📚 Read:  David Henkin, The Postal Age: The Emergence of Modern Communications in Nineteenth-Century America (2007). Introduction and Chapter 4.  🎧 Listen:  &amp;ldquo;The Revolutionary Post&amp;rdquo;, interview with Winifred Gallagher on 99% Invisible (22:55)  ✏️ Write:  No response questions for this week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 7</title>
      <link>https://gwijthoff.github.io/texting/sessions/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gwijthoff.github.io/texting/sessions/7/</guid>
      <description>Note: due to Fall Recess the preceding Monday and Tuesday, there will be no synchronous meeting this week. We will still check in remotely via the class Slack.
Before Class 📚 Read:  Rachael Scarborough King, Writing to the World: Letters and the Origins of Modern Print Genres (2018). Introduction + Chapter 3.  ✏️ Write:  a letter to your classmate answers to these #response-questions:  Rachael Scarborough King defines a bridge genre as “a genre that facilitates change by providing writers and readers with paths across shifting media landscapes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 8</title>
      <link>https://gwijthoff.github.io/texting/sessions/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gwijthoff.github.io/texting/sessions/8/</guid>
      <description>session notes
Reminder: Election Day is in two weeks. Are you all set up to vote?
Also: it&amp;rsquo;s time to begin setting up meetings with me to discuss your final project.
Visitors: Lucas McMahon and Abigail Sargent on &amp;ldquo;Mapping Medieval Metadata,&amp;rdquo; a project that maps lead seals used to enclose correspondence and assure the recipient of the genuineness of the contents in the Byzantine Empire.
Before Class 📚 Read:  Joanne McNeil, Lurking: How a Person Became a User (2020)  Introduction Chapter 3: Visibility Chapter 4: Sharing Closing: End User   Samples of a Byzantine letter and an administrative document, in advance of Lucas and Abigail&amp;rsquo;s visit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 9</title>
      <link>https://gwijthoff.github.io/texting/sessions/9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gwijthoff.github.io/texting/sessions/9/</guid>
      <description>A brief introduction to theories of textuality. Why text is never just &amp;ldquo;information,&amp;rdquo; even when it&amp;rsquo;s a CSV or TXT file. Can data be said to have an &amp;ldquo;author&amp;rdquo; in the textual sense, even if that data has been unconsciously or unwittingly produced?
Before Class 📚 Read:  Treharne and Willan, Text Technologies: A History, Part I: Conceptual Framework, pp. 1–33 Roland Barthes, &amp;ldquo;From Work to Text&amp;rdquo; (1971)  ❀</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
